<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-06-14T09:12:30-05:00</updated><id>https://in2sure.github.io/index.xml</id><title type="html">In2Sure - Distributed Risk Management Foundation</title><subtitle>The world’s first science foundation to promote research, education, and applications of distributed technologies for risk management.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Foundations and Applications of Decentralized Risk Sharing - FADeRiS 2023 @ KU Leuven</title><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/faderis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Foundations and Applications of Decentralized Risk Sharing - FADeRiS 2023 @ KU Leuven" /><published>2023-05-15T09:37:13-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T09:37:13-05:00</updated><id>https://in2sure.github.io/faderis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://in2sure.github.io/faderis">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the website of FADeRiS-2023 @ KU Leuven, the workshop on the Foundations and Applications of Decentralized Risk-Sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risk-sharing mechanisms have been studied for decades in the actuarial literature, starting with the pioneering work of Karl Borch who investigated equilibrium in a reinsurance market in the early 1960s. Decentralized risk-sharing refers to risk-sharing mechanisms under which the participants in a pool decide to share their risks among each other in such a way that the sum all losses paid from the pool matches the sum of the contributions paid by the participants.  As mentioned above, investigating  how to determine ‘fair’ contributions in a decentralized risk-sharing problem is an old research problem in the actuarial and risk-sharing literature. The recent interest in a sharing economy, collaborative consumption and decentralized finance, together with recent advances in technology have led to a renewed academic interest in decentralized risk-sharing mechanisms. Moreover, in practice, peer-to-peer (P2P) or collaborative insurance revives early forms of mutual insurance, where the contributions of the many are used to cover the misfortunes of the few, while keeping insurer’s experience in claim settlement and risk-bearing capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking into account these new practical and theoretical evolutions, we have decided to launch an academic forum for research on decentralized risk-sharing and its applications. FADeRiS-2023 is the first of (hopefully) a series of workshops, with the goal of bringing together researchers active in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is our pleasure and honor to dedicate this first FADeRiS workshop held at KU Leuven to prof. dr. Marc Goovaerts, one of the most brilliant actuarial researchers of his generation and a great mentor for many Belgian and Dutch actuaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jan, Mario, and Michel (the organizers)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:faderis.workshop@gmail.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;faderis.workshop@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organizers acknowledge the financial support of ASTeRISK (eos-asterisk.be), a project funded by the Excellence of Science (EOS) 2021 call by FWO and FRNS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For program details, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/view/faderis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://sites.google.com/view/faderis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>FADeRiS</name></author><category term="conference" /><category term="distributed risk sharing" /><category term="risk management" /><category term="decentralization" /><category term="insurtech" /><summary type="html">Welcome to the website of FADeRiS-2023 @ KU Leuven, the workshop on the Foundations and Applications of Decentralized Risk-Sharing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Decentralized Insurance: Technical Foundation of Business Models</title><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/dencentralized-insurance" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Decentralized Insurance: Technical Foundation of Business Models" /><published>2023-04-25T09:37:13-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-25T09:37:13-05:00</updated><id>https://in2sure.github.io/dencentralized-insurance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://in2sure.github.io/dencentralized-insurance">&lt;p&gt;The book offers an introduction to the technical foundation of decentralized insurance models, for advanced undergraduate students, graduate students and practitioners. The book is self-contained and anyone with a basic knowledge of probability and statistics should be able to follow through the entire book. It adopts a minimalist approach to describe the essential elements and first principles so that readers can get a gist of these models without being overwhelmed with too much technicality. It can be used as a reference for business model designs. The inclusion of exercises and practical examples makes the book suitable for advanced courses on decentralized insurance and risk sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a mix of industry practices and academic models presented in this book. The exposition starts with an overview of historic and current business practices and preliminaries on the mathematics and economics of risk and insurance.  A bird’s-eye view of traditional insurance is provided as a benchmark for various topics to be used in contrast with decentralized insurance. The book then continues with decentralized insurance practices around the world, including online mutual aid originated in China, takaful from the Islamic world, peer-to-peer insurance in the West, catastrophe risk pooling for Carribean countries, etc. Theories of aggregate risk pooling and peer-to-peer risk exchanges are provided for readers to appreciate the mathematical foundation of risk sharing. A unified framework of decentralized insurance is presented to show a structured approach to the economic design of decentralized business models. The book ends with a technical review of blockchain and decentralized finance (DeFi) insurance applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Decentralized-Insurance-Technical-Foundation-Actuarial/dp/3031295587/ref=sr_1_2?crid=2G7JWZ0XF0GOC&amp;amp;keywords=decentralized+insurance&amp;amp;qid=1681589400&amp;amp;sprefix=decentralized+insurance%2Caps%2C111&amp;amp;sr=8-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Runhuan Feng</name></author><category term="decentralized insurance" /><category term="insurance" /><category term="decentralization" /><category term="insurtech" /><category term="fintech" /><summary type="html">The book offers an introduction to the technical foundation of decentralized insurance models, for advanced undergraduate students, graduate students and practitioners. The book is self-contained and anyone with a basic knowledge of probability and statistics should be able to follow through the entire book. It adopts a minimalist approach to describe the essential elements and first principles so that readers can get a gist of these models without being overwhelmed with too much technicality. It can be used as a reference for business model designs. The inclusion of exercises and practical examples makes the book suitable for advanced courses on decentralized insurance and risk sharing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cost-Effectiveness, Fairness and Adverse Selection in Mutual Aid</title><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/cost-effectiveness-fairness-and-adverse-selection-in-mutual-aid" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cost-Effectiveness, Fairness and Adverse Selection in Mutual Aid" /><published>2022-09-13T09:37:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-13T09:37:13-05:00</updated><id>https://in2sure.github.io/cost-effectiveness-fairness-and-adverse-selection-in-mutual-aid</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://in2sure.github.io/cost-effectiveness-fairness-and-adverse-selection-in-mutual-aid">&lt;p&gt;Online mutual aid (MA) is a novel form of risk sharing empowered by InsurTech to provide critical illness coverage without involving an insurer. By shifting from ex-ante premium to ex post sharing, MA platforms regularly publicize the information of confirmed loss cases to their participants, including claimants’ diagnosed diseases,benefits and share contribution per participant. This paper shows that MA’s distinctive “paying after knowing” feature has largely shaped its cost-effectiveness. We first provide a rigorous examination of the underpinning theory and conclude thatMA model’s low coverage cost is achieved through an effective ex-post cost-sharing mechanism. In addition, MA plans suffers unfairness as they differentiate members only by gender and age group of large bandwidths. Using proprietary data on participants’ quitting behavior, our empirical analysis shows that participants are conscious about the public disclosure and confirms the existence of adverse selection due to the lack of actuarial fairness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read More at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3925904&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3925904&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ze Chen, Runhuan Feng, Li Wei, Jiaqi Zhao</name></author><category term="decentralized insurance" /><category term="distributed risk sharing" /><category term="mutual aid" /><category term="insurtech" /><category term="adverse selection" /><category term="risk sharing" /><category term="information disclosure" /><summary type="html">Online mutual aid (MA) is a novel form of risk sharing empowered by InsurTech to provide critical illness coverage without involving an insurer. By shifting from ex-ante premium to ex post sharing, MA platforms regularly publicize the information of confirmed loss cases to their participants, including claimants’ diagnosed diseases,benefits and share contribution per participant. This paper shows that MA’s distinctive “paying after knowing” feature has largely shaped its cost-effectiveness. We first provide a rigorous examination of the underpinning theory and conclude thatMA model’s low coverage cost is achieved through an effective ex-post cost-sharing mechanism. In addition, MA plans suffers unfairness as they differentiate members only by gender and age group of large bandwidths. Using proprietary data on participants’ quitting behavior, our empirical analysis shows that participants are conscious about the public disclosure and confirms the existence of adverse selection due to the lack of actuarial fairness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Multi-period Peer-to-Peer Risk Sharing</title><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/multi-period-p2p-risk-sharing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Multi-period Peer-to-Peer Risk Sharing" /><published>2022-04-06T09:37:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-06T09:37:13-05:00</updated><id>https://in2sure.github.io/multi-period-p2p-risk-sharing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://in2sure.github.io/multi-period-p2p-risk-sharing">&lt;p&gt;Risk sharing has been practiced in various forms in the financial industry. This paper proposes a multi-period risk-sharing mechanism for a group of participants. The design of risk-sharing strategies is based on mean-variance optimizations of participants’ terminal reserves. Such a framework builds a connection between mean-variance optimization for portfolio selection in the finance literature and that for risk sharing in the insurance literature. Building on the most common form of reinsurance – pro-rata treaties, we propose in this work the peer-to-peer (P2P) network for risk sharing. Assuming that multivariate losses are independent over time, we find that the optimal risk-sharing allocation exhibits a three-component structure with the long-term limit and two correction terms. This allows us to show convergence of the risk-sharing solution and the ratios of long-term reserves. We also consider the P2P risk sharing in the dynamic versus the static settings. Furthermore, we study the impact of financial fairness on various risk sharing strategies and their long term limits. The paper provides numerical illustrations of the key research findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read More at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4065099&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4065099&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Samal Abdikerimova, Tim J. Boonen, Runhuan Feng</name></author><category term="decentralized insurance" /><category term="distributed risk sharing" /><category term="risk sharing" /><category term="p2p" /><category term="insurance" /><category term="mean-variance optimization" /><category term="multi-period model" /><category term="catastrophe risk pooling" /><summary type="html">Risk sharing has been practiced in various forms in the financial industry. This paper proposes a multi-period risk-sharing mechanism for a group of participants. The design of risk-sharing strategies is based on mean-variance optimizations of participants’ terminal reserves. Such a framework builds a connection between mean-variance optimization for portfolio selection in the finance literature and that for risk sharing in the insurance literature. Building on the most common form of reinsurance – pro-rata treaties, we propose in this work the peer-to-peer (P2P) network for risk sharing. Assuming that multivariate losses are independent over time, we find that the optimal risk-sharing allocation exhibits a three-component structure with the long-term limit and two correction terms. This allows us to show convergence of the risk-sharing solution and the ratios of long-term reserves. We also consider the P2P risk sharing in the dynamic versus the static settings. Furthermore, we study the impact of financial fairness on various risk sharing strategies and their long term limits. The paper provides numerical illustrations of the key research findings.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Unified Theory of Decentralized Insurance</title><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/a-unified-theory-of-decentralized-insurance" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Unified Theory of Decentralized Insurance" /><published>2022-01-28T08:37:13-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-28T08:37:13-06:00</updated><id>https://in2sure.github.io/a-unified-theory-of-decentralized-insurance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://in2sure.github.io/a-unified-theory-of-decentralized-insurance">&lt;p&gt;Decentralized insurance can be used to describe risk sharing mechanisms under which participants trade risks among each other as opposed to passing risks mostly to an insurer in traditional centralized insurance. There are a wide range of decentralized practices in all kinds of forms developed around the world, including online mutual aid in East Asia, takaful in the Middle East, peer-to-peer insurance in the West, international catastrophe risk pooling by African, Caribbean and Central America countries, etc. There is also a rich literature of risk sharing in academia that offers theoretical bases of other decentralized mechanisms. This work presents a unified mathematical framework to describe the commonalities and the relationships of all these seemingly different business in practice and theoretical models in academia. Such a framework provides a fertile ground for the comparison of existing practices and the design and engineering of hybrid and innovative models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read More at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4013729&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4013729&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Runhuan Feng, Ming Liu, Ning Zhang</name></author><category term="decentralized insurance" /><category term="risk sharing" /><category term="decentralization" /><category term="risk pooling" /><category term="risk transfer" /><category term="p2p" /><category term="insurance" /><category term="takaful" /><category term="mutual aid" /><summary type="html">Decentralized insurance can be used to describe risk sharing mechanisms under which participants trade risks among each other as opposed to passing risks mostly to an insurer in traditional centralized insurance. There are a wide range of decentralized practices in all kinds of forms developed around the world, including online mutual aid in East Asia, takaful in the Middle East, peer-to-peer insurance in the West, international catastrophe risk pooling by African, Caribbean and Central America countries, etc. There is also a rich literature of risk sharing in academia that offers theoretical bases of other decentralized mechanisms. This work presents a unified mathematical framework to describe the commonalities and the relationships of all these seemingly different business in practice and theoretical models in academia. Such a framework provides a fertile ground for the comparison of existing practices and the design and engineering of hybrid and innovative models.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Peer-to-Peer Multi-Risk Insurance and Mutual Aid</title><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/p2p-multi-risk-insurance-and-mutual-aid" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Peer-to-Peer Multi-Risk Insurance and Mutual Aid" /><published>2021-10-04T09:37:13-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-04T09:37:13-05:00</updated><id>https://in2sure.github.io/p2p-multi-risk-insurance-and-mutual-aid</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://in2sure.github.io/p2p-multi-risk-insurance-and-mutual-aid">&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer (P2P) insurance is a decentralized network in which participants pool their resources together to compensate those who suffer losses. It is a revival of a centuries-old practice in many ancient societies where members care for each other’s financial needs in the event of misfortune. With the aid of internet technology, P2P insurance is becoming a transparent, high-tech and low-cost alternative to traditional insurance and is viewed by many as a huge disruptor to the traditional insurance industry in the same way Uber is to the taxi industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fast-changing landscape in this field, there has been no previous academic literature on the theoretical underpinning of P2P insurance. This paper presents the first effort to build the framework for the design and engineering of mutual aid and P2P insurance. Most of existing business models in practice, whether traditional or P2P, are developed to insure against a particular risk, such as critical illness, accidental deaths, property damage, etc. However, even with the same type of risk, not all peers can be of the same loss distribution due to different age cohort, health status, or property conditions, etc. While differential pricing has well developed for traditional insurance, the fair allocation of cost for P2P insurance is not yet well understood. This paper presents a variety of P2P insurance/mutual aid models that facilitate the exchange of multiple risks and enable peers with different needs to financially support each other in a transparent and actuarially fair way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read More at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3505646&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3505646&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Samal Abdikerimova, Runhuan Feng</name></author><category term="decentralized insurance" /><category term="distributed risk sharing" /><category term="peer-to-peer" /><category term="insurance" /><category term="decentralization" /><category term="disintermediation" /><category term="mutual aid" /><category term="law of large numbers" /><category term="insurtech" /><category term="fintech" /><summary type="html">Peer-to-peer (P2P) insurance is a decentralized network in which participants pool their resources together to compensate those who suffer losses. It is a revival of a centuries-old practice in many ancient societies where members care for each other’s financial needs in the event of misfortune. With the aid of internet technology, P2P insurance is becoming a transparent, high-tech and low-cost alternative to traditional insurance and is viewed by many as a huge disruptor to the traditional insurance industry in the same way Uber is to the taxi industry.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Peer-to-Peer Risk Sharing with an Application to Flood Risk Pooling</title><link href="https://in2sure.github.io/p2p-risk-sharing-with-application-to-flood" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Peer-to-Peer Risk Sharing with an Application to Flood Risk Pooling" /><published>2021-02-18T08:37:13-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-18T08:37:13-06:00</updated><id>https://in2sure.github.io/p2p-risk-sharing-with-application-to-flood</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://in2sure.github.io/p2p-risk-sharing-with-application-to-flood">&lt;p&gt;In contrast with classic centralized risk sharing, a novel peer-to-peer risk sharing framework is proposed. The presented framework aims to devise a risk allocation mechanism that is structurally decentralized, Pareto optimal, and mathematically fair. An explicit form for the pool allocation ratio matrix is derived, and convex programming techniques are applied to determine the optimal pooling mechanism in a constrained variance reduction setting. A tiered hierarchical generalization is also constructed to improve computational efficiency. As an illustration, these techniques are applied to a flood risk pooling example. It is shown that peer-to-peer risk sharing techniques provide an economically viable alternative to traditional flood policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read More at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3754565&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3754565&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Runhuan Feng, Chongda Liu, Stephen Michael Taylor</name></author><category term="decentralized insurance" /><category term="distributed risk sharing" /><category term="peer-to-peer" /><category term="insurance" /><category term="risk sharing" /><category term="Pareto optimality" /><summary type="html">In contrast with classic centralized risk sharing, a novel peer-to-peer risk sharing framework is proposed. The presented framework aims to devise a risk allocation mechanism that is structurally decentralized, Pareto optimal, and mathematically fair. An explicit form for the pool allocation ratio matrix is derived, and convex programming techniques are applied to determine the optimal pooling mechanism in a constrained variance reduction setting. A tiered hierarchical generalization is also constructed to improve computational efficiency. As an illustration, these techniques are applied to a flood risk pooling example. It is shown that peer-to-peer risk sharing techniques provide an economically viable alternative to traditional flood policies.</summary></entry></feed>